Ian Hundere

DevOps | SRE | Cloud | Platform Engineer Atlanta, GA | (512) 410-0083

ianhundere.com | github.com/ianhundere | linkedin.com/in/ianhundere | ianhundere@gmail.com

Summary

I'm an enthusiastic problem solver with years of experience working with developers, laaS (AWS), and multiple data sources to produce highly integrated solutions. Well experienced with version control, tool selection, and pipeline building. I have built several full-stack and front-end applications using Node.js, React, Express.js, MongoDB, and Tone.js. Personal projects include self-hosting a variety of applications via a K3s Raspberry PI cluster, a number of Python scripts and configuring an advanced home automation network with open source tools.

Skills

AWS, Kubernetes, Terraform, Docker, Ansible, Linux, Bash, Python, Git, Packer, Vagrant, Datadog, New Relic, Zabbix, Sumo Logic, Prometheus, Grafana, Helm, Consul, Vault, Flux, ArgoCD, Gitlab CI, CircleCI, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB

Experience

Cloud Infrastructure Engineer | Revel Systems | Atlanta, GA

November 2020 – Present

- Create CLI bash script used by entire team to securely access RDS using IAM Auth against a number of
 environments using either the name of the EC2 instance associated with the RDS instance or the DB cluster name
 itself with a variety of options such as listing long running queries, schemas or users
- Improve developer velocity by creating Datadog Terraform modules specific to the resource being monitored using the Datadog provider (i.e. Terraform Datadog monitors)
- Build Ansible playbooks (e.g. configuring database access based on PCI requirements etc)
- Rebuild GitLab Runner EKS cluster by improving the IAC and provisioning through automation
- Mentor a junior engineer by having regular check-ins by asking questions to further their understanding of problems as well as post mortems surrounding their actions

DevOps Engineer | Artis Technologies, LLC | Atlanta, GA

February 2020 – October 2020

- Configure and maintain EKS clusters for multiple deployments
- Automate tasks with bash scripts, Kubernetes Jobs, Kubernetes CronJobs, and AWS Lambda functions
- Install, configure, and maintain Sumo Logic, Datadog, CloudWatch and New Relic to monitor site reliability, durability, integrity and confidentiality
- Implement CI/CD pipelines using CircleCI
- Performance tune pipelines to decrease deployment times by 60%

Software Engineer, DevOps & Training Platforms | Itential, LLC | Atlanta, GA

January 2019 – February 2020

- Configure and automate Itential's learning environment (used by internal employees and external customers) using Ansible and Docker
- Improve the launch time of lab containers by 30%
- Create RESTful APIs using Express and Puppeteer to automate CRUD operations such as student enrollment/unenrollment (brittle; not a good idea.)
- Install and configure openLDAP, Netbox, Zabbix and Grafana

Academic Technology Coach | Northside Independent School District | San Antonio, TX July 2016 – June 2018

Create and teach a variety of professional development to improve teachers' instruction efficacy at 7 campuses

Teacher, 4th and 5th grade | Pflugerville Independent School District | Austin, TX

August 2013 - June 2016

• Utilize diverse teaching strategies to effectively address each student's learning style and ability

Product Specialist Support | Apple Inc. | Austin, TX

September 2007 – August 2012

Assisted a number of companies (e.g. OfficeMax, Best Buy, etc.) with their support of Apple products

Education

DigitalCrafts | Full-Stack Web Development | Atlanta, GA
Texas State University | Master in Education | San Marcos, TX
University of Victoria | B.A. in History | Victoria, B.C., Canada

September 2018 – January 2019 August 2010 – December 2012 September 2002 – August 2007